<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2022-07-25T00:38:02.364Z</id>
    <title>surveyor community::feeds</title>
    <updated>2022-07-25T00:38:02.364Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What will be the best procedure to check column verticality]]></title>
        <id>https://landsurveyorsunited.com/forum/topics/what-will-be-the-best-procedure-to-check-column-verticality</id>
        <link href="https://landsurveyorsunited.com/forum/topics/what-will-be-the-best-procedure-to-check-column-verticality"/>
        <updated>2022-07-20T18:10:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am on a job site where I am building a facility.
I have to layout pile, anchor bolt and check the pipe rack column to see if is vertical.
Is someone can tell me what will be the best procedure using Trimble Vx Robotic Total Station on the field to check column verticality and produce a QA/QC report  showing the deviation (mm)?
I never done this before (producing a QA/QC report  showing the deviation or Tilt calculation) Is someone can help me on that?
Thank's in advance]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Land Surveyor Community Forum - Land Surveyors United - Global Surveying Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surveying Works For Roads Construction]]></title>
        <id>https://landsurveyorsunited.com/forum/topics/surveying-works-for-roads-construction</id>
        <link href="https://landsurveyorsunited.com/forum/topics/surveying-works-for-roads-construction"/>
        <updated>2022-07-10T04:17:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Land Surveying Works for Roads Construction Using SurveyingX Mobile App
 


Download the App From Google Play Store:
https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.Surveying360.SurveyingX]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Land Surveyor Community Forum - Land Surveyors United - Global Surveying Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hawaii, East side, surveying in Battery A. Cr. Feb. 1942]]></title>
        <id>https://landsurveyorsunited.com/photo/hawaii-east-side-surveying-in-battery-a-cr-feb-1942</id>
        <link href="https://landsurveyorsunited.com/photo/hawaii-east-side-surveying-in-battery-a-cr-feb-1942"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T18:48:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hawaii, East side, surveying in Battery A. Cr. Feb. 1942]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>📸 Land Surveying Photos - Land Surveyors United - Global Surveying Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Um... caption this setup...]]></title>
        <id>https://landsurveyorsunited.com/photo/um-caption-this-setup</id>
        <link href="https://landsurveyorsunited.com/photo/um-caption-this-setup"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T18:48:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 15 years of land surveying photograph curation as a global community of surveyors. Picture yourself as a land surveyor in the largest collection of surveying photos anywhere on the internet.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>📸 Land Surveying Photos - Land Surveyors United - Global Surveying Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vic Al Nahyan Crew]]></title>
        <id>https://landsurveyorsunited.com/photo/vic-al-nahyan</id>
        <link href="https://landsurveyorsunited.com/photo/vic-al-nahyan"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T18:48:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 15 years of land surveying photograph curation as a global community of surveyors. Picture yourself as a land surveyor in the largest collection of surveying photos anywhere on the internet.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>📸 Land Surveying Photos - Land Surveyors United - Global Surveying Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Last shot of the day for one is the first shot for many]]></title>
        <id>https://landsurveyorsunited.com/photo/last-shot-of-the-day-for-one-is-the-first-shot-for-many</id>
        <link href="https://landsurveyorsunited.com/photo/last-shot-of-the-day-for-one-is-the-first-shot-for-many"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T18:48:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 15 years of land surveying photograph curation as a global community of surveyors. Picture yourself as a land surveyor in the largest collection of surveying photos anywhere on the internet.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>📸 Land Surveying Photos - Land Surveyors United - Global Surveying Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sunset Surveying]]></title>
        <id>https://landsurveyorsunited.com/photo/bogdan-sabin-lefter</id>
        <link href="https://landsurveyorsunited.com/photo/bogdan-sabin-lefter"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T18:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bogdan Sabin Lefter]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>📸 Land Surveying Photos - Land Surveyors United - Global Surveying Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPS Equipment]]></title>
        <id>https://landsurveyorsunited.com/forum/topics/gps-equipment</id>
        <link href="https://landsurveyorsunited.com/forum/topics/gps-equipment"/>
        <updated>2022-07-07T17:56:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Does anyone have experience with South G6 GPS. I am considering buying one and would like to know pros and cons]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Land Surveyor Community Forum - Land Surveyors United - Global Surveying Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[👷 July Updates Land Surveyors United Members - New Navigation, Jobs, Spreadsheets and More...]]></title>
        <id>https://landsurveyorsunited.com/notes/july-updates-land-surveyors-united-members-new-navigation-jobs-sp</id>
        <link href="https://landsurveyorsunited.com/notes/july-updates-land-surveyors-united-members-new-navigation-jobs-sp"/>
        <updated>2022-07-05T20:43:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update for Members:   New Navigation and quick access to tools and forums
Big welcome to all of our new members on Land Surveyors United!   Just 100 more surveyors and we'll be at 20,000 worldwide!  Wow!   We should be running into one another at the grocery store!
Surveyor Jobs |  Surveyor Radio  |  Find or Sell Used Equipment |  Mentorship
 
Here are a few new features and resources to check out!
Land Surveyor Learning Center
Our new Land Surveyor Learning Center is a place packed with Surveying Tutorials, Drone Surveying Instructional Videos, Surveyor Training and Support, Etc.




👷Surveyor Spreadsheet Tools Wiki
We've been curating surveyor submitted spreadsheets inside the Excel Hub for close to 15 years.  So what we did was combine all of the spreadsheet tools into one wiki for easy finding.












Update Your Profile Today!
Visit Your Profile     |    Edit Profile Settings    |  Follow on Twitter    |  Follow on Facebook
Email not displaying correctly? View it in your browser.
Copyright 2022 Land Surveyors United Community. All Rights Reserved.
Donate to the Land Surveyors United Community to help with expenses]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Surveyor Apps and Community Updates - Land Surveyors United - Global Surveying Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Land Mentor Software License Registration is Now FREE!  Thanks Neighborhood Innovations!]]></title>
        <id>https://landsurveyorsunited.com/articles/land-mentor-software-registration-is-now-free-thanks-neighborhood</id>
        <link href="https://landsurveyorsunited.com/articles/land-mentor-software-registration-is-now-free-thanks-neighborhood"/>
        <updated>2022-07-02T16:49:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Land Mentor Software is Now Free for Land Surveyors United Members!
July 1st, 2022: ‘Land Mentor’ Land Development now free 
Neighborhood Innovations, LLC. is gifting the land development and building  industry to solve many of the growth problems worldwide.  
LandMentor is a ‘System’ that blends technology with an education in advanced  market proven land development planning and housing design methods.  
The education and technology of using LandMentor should decrease the infrastructure needed to develop land between 5-40% compared to current and  past development patterns. For urban redevelopment, the reduction can be  greater than 50%.  
This has obvious economic and environmental benefits to developers, residents, cities and is desperately needed with today’s escalating construction c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Surveying Articles &amp; Presentations - Land Surveyors United - Global Surveying Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[1796 First American Work on Surveying Surveyor Math Mathematics Land Property Moore, Samuel]]></title>
        <id>https://landsurveyorsunited.com/photo/surveyinghistory-1796-first-american-work-on-surveying-surveyor</id>
        <link href="https://landsurveyorsunited.com/photo/surveyinghistory-1796-first-american-work-on-surveying-surveyor"/>
        <updated>2022-06-28T21:02:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[#surveyinghistory
1796 First American Work on Surveying Surveyor Math Mathematics Land Property
Moore, Samuel
An Accurate System of Surveying; in which is contained, I. Decimal Fractions, in a plain, concise, and easy Manner. II. The Extraction of the Square-Root. III. Plane Trigonometry, rectangular and oblique. IV. An exact Method to cast up the Contents of Lands. V. Field Surveying. The Whole being performed without the Use of Scale and Compasses, or a Table of Logarithms. In which is given, some Account of the Variation of the Needle, and the Causes of its Attraction.
Litchfield: T. Collier. 1796. First edition. x, [6], 131 [i.e., 132], [4] pp. 4to. The first American work to be published on surveying, providing an account of the mathematical principles associated with various tasks important to the surveyor. Moore was an experienced surveyor by the time he published this work, and part of the aim of this work is to provide methods superior to those in common use at the time, which Moore believed to be crude. He states in his preface that "[the] original surveys of this Country, so far as my Knowledge (from Acquaintance and Information) extends, are very confused and incorrect... the Cheapness of Lands superseding the Necessity of Precision... This, joined to the Consideration of the large Tracts of appropriated Lands belonging to the United States, renders the Art I am treating of, at this Time peculiarly important." The Treaty of Paris was less than 15 years in the past at the time of publication, and during these years a great deal of land changed ownership. Little did Moore know that less than ten years later the size of the nation would double due to the Louisiana Purchase, making this work even more timely than he had originally surmised.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>📸 Land Surveying Photos - Land Surveyors United - Global Surveying Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Service manuals.]]></title>
        <id>https://landsurveyorsunited.com/forum/topics/service-manuals</id>
        <link href="https://landsurveyorsunited.com/forum/topics/service-manuals"/>
        <updated>2022-06-28T15:15:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where could I find the service manuals for  a sokkia set5f total station and fot the set530r total station ?.
I wil;lapreciate your help.
Jesus F. Pacheco.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Land Surveyor Community Forum - Land Surveyors United - Global Surveying Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>